Guide to the Samuel Shaffer papers, 1948-1982 MS2091
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Chronological files, 1948-1976; MS2091 Series 1; 17 Linear feet
  - Chronological files, 01/01/1973-01/15/1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    [from original finding aid] Tip O'Neill (1/4/73)(Jan 4 1973); Cello--Congress (1/4/72)(1/4/73)(Jan 4 1973); Congress-Vietnam mail (Jan 5 1973); Add Congress (1/5/72)(Jan 5 1973); Congress (1/5/73)(Jan 5 1973); Congressional reform (1/11/73)(Jan 11 1973); With violin (1/12/73)(Jan 12 1973); Add to violin file (1/12/73)(Thomas J.McIntyre)
  - Chronological files, 01/16/1973-01/31/1973 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    [from original finding aid] Congressional reform (1/18/73)(Jan 18 1973); Congress (1/18/73)(Jan 18 1973); Boycott/inaugural (1/19/73)(Jan 19? 1973); Add Congress (Jan 19 1973); Query #8 (Jan 25 1973); Goldman Klein (Vietnam (Domestic))(1/25/73); LBJ/Congress (1/25/73)(Jan 25 1973)(LBJ Funeral); Congressional reform (1/25/73)(Jan 25 1973); Vietnam React (Jan 26 1973); Add to War Powers, etc (1/26/73)(Jan 26 1973); War Powers (1/26/73)(Jan 26 1973); Nation (Martz) from Shaffer-1/27/73 (N15 Burial)
  - Chronological files, 02/01/1973-02/14/1973 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    [from original finding aid] Leisure, Watson, Shaffer, Washington (Query #13--daylight savings (2/1/73)(Feb 1 1973); Cease-fire developments--Congress (2/1/73)(Feb 1 1973); Cello--Congress (2/1/73)(Feb 1 1973) Amnesty-(Congress)(2/1/73)(Feb 1 1973); With Stennis (2/2/73)(Feb 2 1973) Newsmakers, Roeder, Shaffer, Washington, Hartke, (2/2/73)(Feb 2 1973); Correction (2/4/73)(N15 violin)(Feb 3 1973)(Sen.Sam Ervin); Life and Leisure Shaffer (Daylight savings)(Feb 6 1973) Cello--Congress in an uproar (2/8/73)(Feb 8 1973); With Watergate (2/8/73)(Feb 8 1973)
  - Chronological files, 02/15/1973-02/28/1973 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    [from original finding aid] Congress: war reparations (2/15/73)(Feb 15 1973); Add Congress: reparations (2/15/73)(Feb 15 1973); Add Congress: reparations (2/16/73)(Feb 16 1973); Nation, Martz, Alpern, Shaffer, Washington (following wire sent to Wash. Bureau (Senator Barry Goldwater; of Arizona)(Feb 16,1973) With OEO--2/22/73 (Feb 22 1973); Food price cover-Congress (2/22/73)(Feb 22 1973) Congress (2/22/73)(Feb 22 1973); Add to Congress file (2/23/73)(Feb 23 1973) With violin (2/22/73)(Feb 23 1973)
  - Chronological files, 03/01/1973-03/14/1973 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    [from original finding aid] Pat Gray (3/1/73)(Mar 1 1973); Query #2 (Mar 2 1973)(Bob Byrd); Pat Gray (3/8/73)(Mar 8 1973); Impoundment (3/8/73)(Mar 8 1973); Add Impoundment (3/8/73)(Mar 8 1973); With Haldeman (3/8/73)(Mar 8 1973); Oil prices (3/8/73)(Mar 8 1973); City crisis (3/9/73)(Mar 9 1973); Add Gray (3/9/73)(Mar 9 1973); Add to Impoundment-Congress (3/9/73); Correction (3/10/73)(N13 New Mayors); Correction (3/10/73)(N12 Haldeman Tape 5)
  - Chronological files, 03/15/1973-03/31/1973 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    [from original finding aid] Pat Gray (3/15/73)(Mar 15 1973); Violin (3/22/73)(Mar 22 1973); Violin Take II (3/22/73)(Mar 22 1973); With Connally cover (3/22/73)(Mar 22 1973); Watergate-Congress (#722/73)(Mar 23 1973); Add violin (3/23/73)(Mar 23 1973); Nation (Goldman) from Shaffer-3/24/73 (Watergate/Nixon); Vocab.rehab (3/29/73)(Mar 29 1973); Watergate/Congress (Mar 29 1973)
  - Chronological files, 04/1973 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    [from original finding aid] Violin (4/5/73)(Apr 5 1973); With Cambodia (4/5/73)(Apr 5 1973); Congress/veto (4/12/73)(Apr 12 1973); Watergate Add-deal (Apr 13 1973); Medicine Seligmann Shaffer, Washington (4/13/73)(your query #12)(Apr 13 1973)(Atkins diet); Economiker/Congress (4/19/73)(Apr 19 1973) Base closings (4/19/73)(Apr 19 1973); Add to base closing (4/20/73); Violin (Can he govern-Congress)(Apr 26 1973) Brezhnev/Congress (4/26/73)(Apr 26 1973); Add to Brezhnev/Congress (4/27/73)(Apr 27 1973); Add violin (4/27/73)(Apr 27 1973); Kosner, Conway, Shaffer, Washington (wire from McReynolds) (Apr 27 1973)
  - Chronological files, 05/01/1973-05/15/1973 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    [from original finding aid] Connally (5/3/73) (May 3 1973); Violin/Congress (May 3 1973) Add violin (5/3/73) (Richardson); Add violin (4/5/73) (May 4 1973 )(Impeachment proceedings) Cambodia/Congress (5/4/73) (May 4 1973); Add violin (5/4/73) (May 4 1973); Coleman/Watergate (5/4/73); EPA decision -- short (5/10/73) (May 10 1973); Cambodia ( 5/10/73 ) (May 10 1973); Query #6 (May 11 1973) (War); Your query on the origins of American involvement in the war in Vietnam (May 11 1973)
  - Chronological files, 05/16/1973-05/31/1973 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    [from original finding aid] Watergate-violin (5/17/73) (May 17 1973); Cambodia/Congress (5/17/73) (May 17 1973); Add violin (5/730 (May 18 1973 ) (Watergate); Violin (5/18/73)(Price of gold); Nixon -- react (5/23/73 ) (May 23 1973); Democrat's delight (5/31/73) (May 31 1973); With Vietnam (5/31/73) (May 31 1973)
  - Chronological files, 06/1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    [from original finding aid] Correction (6/2/73) (Int 15 Cambodia); Watergate violin-Take III (Jun 7 1973); Cover -- Congress react (6/14/73 ) (Jun 14 1973); Vietnam (Congress )( 6/14/73 ) (Jun 14 1973); Correction (6/16/73 )( Int 27); Brezhnev/Congress ( 6/21/73 ) (Jun 21 1973); Dean - the postponement (6/21/73 ) (Jun 21 1973); Violin-Nixon (Jun 22 1973); Cambodian bombing ( 6/28/73 ) (Jun 28 1973); Add Cambodia (Jun 28 1973); Further add Cambodia (6/29/73); Add Cambodia once again (6/29/73); More on Cambodia ( 6/29/73 ) (Jun 29 1973); Further, further add Cambodia ( 6/29/73 ) (Jun 29 1973); Add Cambodia (6/29/74)(Jun 29 1973) Further add Cambodia (6/29/73)(Jun 29 1973); Hopefully the last Cambodian add tonight (6/29/73) (Jun 29 1973)
  - Chronological files, 07/1973 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    [from original finding aid] With violin (Politics) Take two (Jl 5 1973); Newsmakers from Shaffer (7/573)(Jul 6 1973); With violin (7/12/73)(Jul 12 1973)(Nixon/Watergate); Nation, Martz, Shaffer, Washington (7/13/73)Correction; Violin/Congress (7/16/73)(Jul 19 1973); Cambodian bombing (7/19/73)(Jul 19 1973); Add violin (7/20/73)(Jul 20 1973); Cambodia/Congress (7/26/73)(Jul 26 1973); Klein from Shaffer (7/27/73)(Cambodian); Nation (Martz, Goldman) from Shaffer-7/28/73 (with violin; (tapes)(Jul 28 1973) Violin/Congress (7/26/73)(Jul 28 1973)
  - Chronological files, 08/1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    [from original finding aid] Campaign spending (8/2/73)(Aug 2 1973); With violin (8/2/73)(Aug 2 1973)(Watergate tapes); Violin-add Congress (8/3/73); With ITT box (8/3/73); Washington: ExEducation: Wall St. Journal 7/25/73 (8-4-73); Running react (Congress)(8/16/73)(Aug 16 1973); Add react (8/17/73)(Aug 17 1973); Add react/Congress (8/17/73)(Aug 17 1973); Kissinger/Congress (8/23/73)(Aug 23 1973); Agnew react (8/23/73)(Aug 23 1973); Nixon cover/react (8/23/73)(Aug 23 1973); 7-leaks (Aug 29 1973); Shaffer's Yalta file follows: (Aug 29 1973); Leisure,young, Shaffer, Washington (bicycle (8/29/73)(Aug 29 1973); Sirica running-react (8/30/73)(Aug 30 1973) Sirica running-reaction (8/30/73)(Aug 30 1973)
  - Chronological files, 09/01/1973-10/19/1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    [from original finding aid] Agnew/running (Congress)(Oct 11 1973); With mideast package (10/12/73)(Oct 12 1973); With Ford (10/12/73)(Oct 12 1973); Ford interview (10/13/73)(Oct 13 1973); Add Ford (10/13/73)(Oct 13 1973); Nation from Shaffer (10/13/73)(Oct 13 1973)(Text of a press release from Rep. Rodino's office); Agnew-Ford and Cello (10/18/73)(Oct 18 1973); Violin-Congress and Detente (Take One)(Oct 19 1973); Detente--Take II (Oct 19 1973)
  - Chronological files, 10/20/1973-10/31/1973 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    [from original finding aid] Tapes-Ervin, Stennis (Oct 20 1973); Tapes/Congress Take II (Oct 20 1973) Judiciary Committee (Oct 20 1973); Tapes-Congressional Reaction (Oct 20 1973) Tapes-Congress Reaction (Take Two) (Oct 20 1973); Running--Congress (10/25/73)(Oct 25 1973) Running--Congress Take II (Oct 28 1973); Running-Congress (Take III) and Superviolin (Oct 28 1973); Superviolin and running--Congress press conference react (10/26/73)(Oct 26 1973)
  - Chronological files, 11/01/1973-11/14/1973 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    [from original finding aid] Violin, Ford, Special Prosecution and Attorney Gen.--Senate (Nov 1 1973); Saxbe (11/1/73)(Nov 1 1973); Saxbe (Take II), also for violin Violin/Senate--Take II (11/2/73)(Nov 2 1973); More on Violin/Senate (11/2/73)(nov 2 1973) Jewish vote and mid-east policy (11/2/73)(Nov 2 1973); Violin-running (11/8/73)(Nov 8 1973) Add Violin/running (11/9/73)(Nov 9 1973); Meeting with Congressional leaders (11/9/73)(Nov 9 1973)
  - Chronological files, 11/15/1973-11/30/1973 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    [from original finding aid] Add violin running (11/15/73)(Nov 15 1973); Violin--running/operation candor (11/15/73)(Nov 15 1973); Correction (11/16/73)(N15 Nox)(Nov 17 1973); Cello--running/Congress (11/21/73)(Nov 21 1973); Cello update (Nov 23 1973); Energy cover-Congress reaction (11/21/73)(Nov 21 1973); Violin running (Senate)(Nov 29 1973); Add violin/running/Senate (11/30/73) Nov.30 1973
  - Chronological files, 12/01/1973-12/14/1973 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    [from original finding aid] Campaign financing (11/6/73)(Dec 6 1973); Jewish lobby (11/6/73)(12/6/73)(Dec 6 1973); Violin/Congress (12/6/73)(Dec 6 1973); Add violin/Congress (12/6/73)(Dec 7 1973); ARMS Balance-Salt II (Congress)(12/13/74)(Dec 13 1973); Violin and cello (12/13/73)(Dec 13 1973); Violin--politics/Congress (12/13/73)(Dec 13 1973)
  - Chronological files, 12/15/1973-12/31/1973 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    [from original finding aid] Further add to violin/Congress/cello (12/14/73)(Dec 14 1973); Nation, Martz; Newsmakers, Roeder; Periscope, Conway,; Shaffer, Washington (Dec 14 1973)(Sen. Alan Cranston) Add violin/running/politics (12/14/73)(Dec 14 1973)(Brock); Add to violin/cello on Nixon finances (12/14/73)(Dec 14 1973); (Sen. Walter F."Fritz"Mondale, Nixon); Add Casey (12/14/73)(Dec 14 9173) '; Goldman from Shaffer (12/14/73)(Dec 14 1973)(Casey); Cello--Congress (12/20/73)(Checks and balances; the 1st.; session of the 93rd. Congress) Politics (Dec 21 1973); Violin-Xmas, referendum, add (12/28/73)(Dec 28 1973) N14 Violin
  - Chronological files, 01/1974 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    [from original finding aid] With cover/Congress (1/17/74)(Jan 17 1974); To North from Shaffer (1/17/74)(Nixon and taxes)(Jan 17 1974); Advisory on foreign aid (1/18/74)(Jan 18 1974) Violin/Congress (1/24/74)(Jan 24 1974); Scott (1/24/74)(Jan 24 1974) Add Scott (1/25/74 )(Jan 25 1974); Overseas Parker Wash Shaffer (In re query ARDA report--) (Jan 30 1974); Violin/Congress (1/31/74)(Jan 31 1974)
  - Chronological files, 02/1974 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    [from original finding aid] Violin/Mansfield (2/1/74)(Feb 1 1974); Nation, Martz, Goldman from Shaffer--2/2/74 Violin/Congress; (my file No.27 of 1/31) Pay raises (2/7/74)(Feb 7 1974); Controls (2/7/74)(Feb 7 1974); Violin-The confrontation (Senate)(2/7/74)(Feb 7 1974) Panama (2/8/74) "Legislating an end to Foreign Aid" Statement by Senator J.W.; Fulbright U.S.Senate Pa. election (Feb 8 1974); Add'pay raise (2/7/74); Solzhenitsyn--Congress (2/14/74)(Feb 14.1974); Aiken (2/14/74)(Feb 15 1974); Further add Solzhenitsyn/Congress--2/15/74 (Feb 15 1974); Add Solzhenitsyn/Congress (2/15/74)(Feb 15 1974); With violin/Congress (2/21/74)(Feb 21 1974); Add violin/Congress (2/22/74)(Feb 22 1974); Further add violin/Congress (2/22/74)(Feb 22 1974) Correction (2/23/74)(N14 Violin); Biz, Margello, Shaffer, Washington (energy) Violin;and White House/Congress (2/28/74)(Feb 28 1974)
  - Chronological files, 03/01/1974-03/15/1974 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    [from original finding aid] Violin Congress/react (Mar 1 1974); Add violin/Congress (3/1/74); Hearst kidnap guery (Mar 7 1974); Violin/Congress (3/7/74)(Mar 7 1974); Impeach? Primer? Senate (3/13/74)(Mar 13 1974); Impeachment Primer Senate--Take II (3/14/74)(Mar 14 1974); Death Penalty (3/14/74)(Mar 14 1974); European Leadall and Kissinger Week (3/14/74)(Mar 14 1974); With Violin-Congress (3/15/74)(Mar 15 1974)
  - Chronological files, 03/16/1974-03/31/1974 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    [from original finding aid] Buckley (3/21/74)(Mar 21 1974); Add violin/Buckley (3/22/74)(Mar 22 1974); Violin/- Congress (3/28/74)(Mar 28 1974); De Frank reports (Mar 28 1974); Violin Sun-times (Mar 28 1974)(Impeachment); Lead all/Kissinger-Congress (Mar 29 1947)
  - Chronological files, 04/1974 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    [from original finding aid] With violin political response 4/4/74 (Apr 4 1974); Violin/Congress updater (4/5/74)(Apr 5 1974)(Percy); Violin-Congress updater (4/5/74)(Apr 5 1974); Add, add violin/Congress (4/5/74)(Apr 5 1974); Violin/Michigan election (4/11/74)(Apr 11 1974); Iraham from Shaffer (Ford react)(Apr 12 1974); Add violin--4/12/74 (Apr 12 1974); Elliott, Kosner, Martz from Shaffer (4/12/74)(The"T?"District"(Apr 12 1974); Add violin (4/18/74)(Apr 18 1974); Violin (4/18/74)-Congress (Apr 18 1974); For violin-congress (4/19/74) (Apr 19 1974); Add violin 4/25/74) Apr 25 1974) (Jovits on Balance of power); Correction to Nation, Martz, Goldman from Shaffer, Wash,(Re my no of today with violin); Violin-Congress (4/25/74)(Apr 25 1974); Query #14/Kennedy (4/25/74)(Apr 25 1974); Atomic threat (4/26/74)(Apr 26 1974); With violin (4/26/&$) (Apr 26 1974); New Desk, Vermil^ion from Shaffer, Wash (Apr 29 1974)(Heidi)
  - Chronological files, 05/1974 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    [from original finding aid] Violin/Congress react (5/2/74)(May 2 1974); Jack Conway from Shaffer May 3, 1974 (May 3 1974); Newsmakers, Roederf Shaffer, Washington(Gurney (5/3/74)(May 3, 1974); Another add violin (or once more into the breach, dear friends) 5/3/74 (May 3 1974); Last add violin (one hopes) 5/3/74 (May 3, 1974); Further, further add violin (5/3/74) Add violin (5/3/74)(May 3 1974); Further add violin (5/3/74)(May 3 1974) Violin (5/9/74)(May 9 1974); Nation, Martz, Goldman, Shaffer, Washington (5/9/74)(May 9 1974)(Nixon); Rodino (5/10/74)(May 10 1974); Ford as President Take I (5/10/74)(May 10 1974); Ford--take II (5/10/74)(May 10 1974); Add violin/Congress (5/10/74)(May 10 1974); Further, further add violin (5/10/74); (Goldwater Interview by Sam Shaffer)(May 15 1974); Add Fulbright (May 18 1974); Fulbright (including Q and A)(5/16/74)(May 16 1974); Nation, Martz, Shaffer, Washington, Goldwater Interview; Violin Congress (5/16/74)(May 16 1974)
  - Chronological files, 06/1974-07/1974 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    [from original finding aid] Summit Ill/Congress (7/3/74)(Jul 3 1974)(Jul 3 1974); Cover/Senate (7/3/74)(Jul 3 1974); Gurney (7/11/74)(Jul 11 1974); Violin--Take II (7/11/74)(Jul 11 1974); Violin (Senate)--7/11/74 (Jul 11 1974); Violin-Impeachment (Jul 12 1974); Violin-the? leadership?--7/18/74 (Jul 18 1974); Cover (7/25/74)(Jul 25 1974)
  - Chronological files, 08/0l/1974-08/14/1974 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    [from original finding aid] Procedures--Senate (8/1/74)(Aug 1 1974); Violin-Senate (8/1/74)(Aug 1 1974); Add violin (8/2/74)(Aug 2 1974); Add violin (8/2/74)(Aug 2 1974); Add violin-Nixon amnesty (8/2/74)(Aug 2 1974); Nation, Goldman from Shaffer (8/2/74)(Rhodes decision)(Aug 2 1974); Nation, Martz Shaffer-8/3/74 (Add violin)(Aug 3 1974) Correction (8/3/74)(N13 Senate (Precede)(Aug 3 1974); Kasner, Martin, Goldman from Shaffer--8/3/74 (Griffin letter)(Aug 3 1974); Nation, Goldman, Shaffer, Washington violin (8/8/74); (Aug 8 1974)(Abdication-smoking gun) Immunity and violin/Brooke (8/9/74)(Aug 9 1974); Add violin (Nixon's post midnite calls)(Aug 9 1974); Violin White House meetings (8/9/74)(Aug 9 1974); Correction (8/10/74)(N35 Violin)
  - Chronological files, 08/l5/1974-08/31/1974 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    [from original finding aid] Violin-(Take I)-Congress (8/15/74)(Aug 15 1974); Violin Congress take I (Aug 15 1974); Violin-Take II (the veep)(8/15/74)(Aug 15 1974); Biz, Ruby, Shaffer, Washington (8/15/74)(Economy LEDE--; Fordonomics)(Aug 15 1974) Amnesty (8/22/74)(Aug 22 1974); Rocky Profile and money (8/22/74)(Aug 22 1974); Violin--the Senate and Rocky (8/22/74)(Aug 22 1974) Violin/Rockefeller (8/28/74)(Aug 28 1974); Nixon and Watergate (8/28/74)(Aug 28 1974); Nixon (8/28/74)(Aug 28 1974) Cello Conservatives (8/28/74)(Aug 29 1974); Nixon (8/29/74)(Aug 29 1974) Mideast-Congress and Israel (Aug 29 1974)
  - Chronological files, 09/01/1974-09/15/1974 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    [from original finding aid] Amnesty-Senate (9/5/74)(Sep 5 1974); Query #18 (Sep 6 1974); Haig (Sep 6 1974); Reaction-Political, Congress (Take II)(Sept.8, 1974); Violin (Senate)(9/12/74)(Sep 12 1974); Add pardon/Senate (9/13/74)(Sep 13 1974)
  - Chronological files, 09/16/1974-09/30/1974 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    [from original finding aid] CIA (9/19/74)(Sep 9 1974); Query #6 (Sep 19 1974)(NATO); Haig/Congress (9/19/74)(Sep 19 1974); Ford Week (9/19/74)(Sep 19 1974); Add Fordweek (Sep 20 1974); Amnesty/Congress (9/19/74)(Sept 19 1974); Add CIA (Sep 20 1974); Leadall/Kissinger(9/20/74)(Sep 20 1974)(aid to Turkey); Kennedy (Sept 25 1974)(Sep 25 1974); Nixon/Congress (9/27/74)(Sep 27 1974); Betty Ford - Political Impact - Take II
  - Chronological files, 10/01/1974-10/15/1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    [from original finding aid] Note: In my file I mentioned four votes on the Turkish amendment (Oct 3 1974); Senate outlook (10/3/74)(Oct 3 1974); Violin-Ford and Congress (10/3/74)(Oct 3 1974); Add Ford (10/4/74)(Oct 4 1974)(Turkish aid); Query #15 (10/10/74)(Oct 10 1974); Violin--Ford/Congress (10/10/74)(Oct 10 1974); Rockefeller (10/11/74)(Oct 11 1974); Add Rocky (10/11/74)(Oct 11 1974); Updating the Turkish aid story (10/11/74)(Oct 11 1974)
  - Chronological files, 10/16/1974-10/31/1974 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    [from original finding aid] Violin-Ford react and Turkish aid veto (10/17/74)(Oct 17 1974); Rockefeller-Senate (10/17/74)(Oct 17 1974); Add Rocky (10/17/74)(Oct 17 1974); Trade bill (10/18/74)(Oct 18 1974); Int 16 Leadall (Oct 19 1974); Rocky/taxes (10/19/74)(Oct 19 1974); Rocky--Goldwater Book; Violin (10/24/74)(Oct 24 1974); Rocky (10/24/740(Oct 24 1974); Kosner, Martz, Shaffer (10/25/74)(Rocky advisory)(Oct 25 1974); Rockefeller-Goldwater React (10/25/74)(Oct 25 1974); Overseas, Parker, Shaffer, Washington (query #17 10/25/74)(Harvard Biz-Proxmire)(Oct 25 1974)
  - Chronological files, 11/1974 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    [from original finding aid] Violin/Congress (Plus Congress and economy)(11/7/74)(Nov 7 1974); Query #21 (Nov 7 1974); To Violin and politicker (11/15/74)(Nov 15 1974); Gen. Brown (11/15/74)(Nov 15 1974); Rocky (11/15/74)(Nov 15 1974); Cover package--running/Congress (11/21/74)(Nov 21 1974); Congress (11/21/74)(Nov 21 1974); Add Congress (11/22/74)(Nov 22 1974); Add Congress (11/22/74)(Nov 22 1974); With Rocky (11/22/74)(Nov 22 1974); With Mondale (11/22/74)(Nov 22 1974); White House structure (11/27/74)(Nov 27 1974); Ford cover (The Senate View)(11/27/74)(Nov 27 1974)
  - Chronological files, 12/1974-02/1975 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    [from original finding aid] With Dems and Congress (12/5/74) (Dec 5 1974); Overseas, Parker, Shaffer, Washington (foreign aid) (12/5/74)(Dec 5 1974); With Mills (12/5/74); With Violin (12/12/74)(Dec 12 1974); Trade Bill (12/12/74)(Dec 12 1974); With Violin (12/13/74)(Dec 13 1974); Levi (12/13/74)(Dec 13 1974); To; Business (Margello) from Shaffer--12/14/74 (Trade Bill)(Dec 14 1974); Congress (12/19/74)(Dec 19 1974); Inside White House (12/19/74)(Dec 19 1974); Newsmakers, Roeder, Shaffer, Washington (Ervin 12/19/74)(Dec 19 1974); Media, Martin, Shaffer, Washington (query #20)(12/19/74)(Dec 19 1974); Levi (12/19/74)(Dec 19 1974); Trade/Leadall (12/20/74)(Dec 20 1974); Add trade/Leadall (12/20/74)(Dec 20 1974); Leadall/add (12/20/74)(Dec 20 1974); Overseas, Keating, Shaffer, Washington,Foreign aid(12/20/74)(Dec 20 1974); CIA/Congress (12/24/74)(Dec 26 1974); Taxes (12/26/74)(Dec 26 1974); Correction (12/28/74)(Biz 17 Lede); Wilbur Mills (12/31/74)(Dec 31 1974); Add Violin/cello (2/7/75) Unemployment react (Feb 7 1975)(Unemployment statistics); Further add Violin/cello (217)(Feb 7 1975); Violin/cello (2/13/75)(Feb 13 1975)(Senate)(Domenici); Query #6 (Feb 14 1975)(Sen. Harrison"Pete"Williams); Add Violin (2/14/75)(Feb 14 1975)(Brock); Biz, Margello, Shaffer, Washington (Mrs.Hills (2/14/75); Add Mrs.Hills (2/14/75); Correction (2/15/75)(NA608 Violin)(Feb 15 1975); Ford/Congress (2/20/75)(Feb 20 1975); Abortion cover (2/20/75)(Feb 20 1975)
  - Chronological files, 01/01/1975-01/20/1975 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Chronological files, 01/21/1975-01/31/1975 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Chronological files, 02/01/1975-02/20/1975 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Chronological files, 02/21/1975-02/28/1975 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Chronological files, 03/1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    [from original finding aid] Cambodia (3/6/75)(Mar.6 1975); Ford and Congress/cello (3/6/75)(Mar 6 1975); Add leadall--as per phoner (3/7/75)(Mar 7 1975); Further add leadall (3/7/75)(Mar 7 1975); Further add leadall (3/7/75); Cover-Goldwater (3/12/75)(Mar 12 1975); Cambodia (3/12/75)(Mar 12 1975); Add Congress (3/13/75); Further add Cambodia (3/13/75)(Mar 13 1975); Note: Secretary of Agriculture; Cello-Congress (3/12/75)(Mar 12 1975); Ronald Reagan/Hugh Scott 3/13/75 (Mar 13 1975); Add Cambodia (3/13)(Mar 13 1975); Further add Congress (3/13/75)(Mar 13 1975)
  - Chronological files, 04/01/1975-10/1975 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    [from original finding aid] Energy-Ford Meeting (July 24 1975); Politics-The Second half; Add Politics-Shaffer (Jul 29 1975); White House leadership meeting on Mid-East (Sep 5 1975); Goldman from Shaffer Oct.9? (taxes)(Oct 9 1975)
  - Chronological files, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    [from original finding aid] Final stories of the; Presidential Campaign Issues Box (8/18/76); Running (8/18/76) Dole (8/19/76); Veepstakes (8/20/76) Dole react (8/20/76)
- Correspondence, 1979-1982; MS2091 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains correspondence. The letters date from 1979-82. These letters are business and congratulatory correspondence pertaining to Shaffer's book, "On and Off the Floor." There are letters from Shaffer and letters to Shaffer. The letters written by Shaffer between June 1979 and January 1982 concerning publication and, promotion of "On and Off the Floor." Shaffer in some instances, identifies the recipient of a specific letter by means of hand-written notation at the top of that particular letter. Among the several recipients identified in this manner are: Herbert Gordon (editor of Shaffer's book), former President Gerald Ford, and Peter Derow (Chairman and President of Newsweek in February 1981). Other letters are original or photocopied business and congratulatory letters received by either Shaffer or the staff at Newsweek Books between February 1979 and October 1982 regarding "On and Off the Floor." The subject matter of these is either promotional comments for the book, expressions of gratitude for the receipt of a copy of the book, or messages of congratulations on the publication of the book. A few of the letters deal with royalties for the book. Many of the correspondents of these letters are well-known; others are associated with Newsweek.
  - Coorespondence, Letters from Shaffer (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Shaffer re: On and Off the Floor, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Shaffer re: On and Off the Floor, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Shaffer re: On and Off the Floor, 03/1980-04/1980 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Shaffer re: On and Off the Floor, 05/1980-12/1980 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Shaffer re: On and Off the Floor, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 13)
- Book typescript, undated; MS2091 Series 3; 2 Linear feet